# **Shah Syed**

## **Programmer Analyst**

Houston, TX - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Shah-Syed/0c761011e919d5a4

Experienced Software Engineer with 2 years of experience in IT industry and currently pursuing a Master's degree in Computer Science from University of Houston - Clear Lake. Having worked on Struts 1.x framework as well as UI design, I am proficient in Java Servlets, MVC, client and server side validations, use CSS, JSP and JavaScript to make the application user friendly. Also, developed mobile applications in Swift and worked on projects involving multithreading. With my skill set and enthusiasm to explore new fields of Computer Science, I am certain I will be an asset to your company.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Programmer Analyst**

Cognizant Technology Solutions - Chennai, Tamil Nadu - August 2014 to October 2015

Project: CALM (Centralized Authentication Login Mechanism)

- > Developed enhancements for the existing login application using Struts 1.x Java MVC framework
- > Developed JSP pages for different modules of the login application making them compatible with different screen sizes uses CSS media queries and performed validations using JavaScript
- > Implemented scripts using jQuery and JavaScript to enhance user experience
- > Extensively worked with CSS to enhance the view of the web pages
- > Implemented scheduled jobs in Java to access the user information from LDAP and create CSV files based on the requirement
- > Wrote SQL queries for the PL/SQL jobs to access and modify user information in the production database.
- > Provided continued maintenance and development of bug fixes for existing web application.
- > Consistently met deadlines and requirements for all production work orders.
- > Performed regression and system level testing to verify software quality and functions before it was released.
- > Prepared test cases for the developed enhancements of the existing web application.

## **Programmer Analyst Trainee**

Cognizant Technology Solutions - Chennai, Tamil Nadu - November 2013 to July 2014

Tamil Nadu, India

## **EDUCATION**

## Master of Science in Computer Science in Computer Science

University of Houston - Houston, TX January 2016 to Present

#### Research

Osmania University March 2017

# Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science and Engineering in Database Management Systems

Graduate School Fund September 2009 to May 2013

# SKILLS

database. (1 year), Java (1 year), JavaScript (1 year), jQuery (1 year), SQL (1 year)

# LINKS

http://linkedin.com/in/s2emaduddin

# ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, HTML, Swift, SQL, Javascript, jQuery, C, PHP

Operating Systems: Windows Family, LINUX/UNIX, Mac OS

IDE: Eclipse, Xcode

Database Environments: MySQL, SQL Server Management Studio

Software: MS Office, Putty, Wireshark